<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons humbly offer'd for a law to enact the castration, or gelding, of Popish ecclesiastics, as the best way to prevent the growth of popery in England.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 40 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B02912</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D843A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R175925</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52614599</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52614599</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175823</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B02912)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175823)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2752:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons humbly offer'd for a law to enact the castration, or gelding, of Popish ecclesiastics, as the best way to prevent the growth of popery in England.</title>
                  <author>Defoe, Daniel, 1661?-1731.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed and are to be sold by A. Baldwin ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Attributed to Daniel Defoe. Cf. Moore Smith, G.C. An unrecognized work of Defoe's? In the Review of English studies, v. 5, no. 17, p. 64-66.</note>
                  <note>Not accepted by John Robert Moore as Defoe's; not listed by Boston Pub. Lib. cat. of The Defoe Coll. Cf. NUC pre-1956.</note>
                  <note>Impefect: print show-through with some loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Catholic Church --  England --  Controversial literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Anti-Catholicism --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:175823:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>REASONS Humbly Offer'd For a LAW to Enact The Caſtration, or Gelding, OF <hi>Popiſh Eccleſiaſtics,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As the Beſt Way to Prevent the Growth of Popery IN ENGLAND.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed, and are to be Sold by <hi>A. Baldwin</hi> in <hi>Warwick-Lane.</hi> 1700.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:175823:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:175823:2"/>
            <head>Reaſons Humbly offer'd for a Law to Enact the Caſtration or Geld<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Popiſh Eccleſiaſtics, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>THE Honorable Houſe of Commons having been pleaſed to take into their Conſideration the unaccountable growth of Popery amongſt us of late, and to appoint a Committee to conſider of Ways and Means for preventing the ſame: It is thought fit, among the croud of Propoſals for that end, to publiſh what follows.</p>
            <p>We may, without intrenching upon the Province of Divines, make bold to aſſert, That when the Church of <hi>Rome</hi> is call'd in the Sacred Scriptures, <hi>The Mother of Harlots, and of the Abominations of the Earth;</hi> there's ſomething elſe meant by it than a mere Religious Impurity, or going a whoring after falſe Gods, as their Saints and Angels, and multitudes of Mediators between God and Men, undoubtedly are. We need but caſt our Eye upon <hi>Platina</hi>'s Lives of the Popes, and turn over a few leaves of the Hiſtories of moſt Nations of <hi>Europe,</hi> to be convinc'd that the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy have ever ſince the Pope's Uſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation been branded with Uncleanneſs. The wanton Obſervation made by <hi>Henry</hi> the <hi>4th</hi> of <hi>France,</hi> as he paſſed one day betwixt a Fri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary and a Nunnery, <hi>That the latter was the Barn, and the former were the Thraſhers,</hi> was found to have too much of truth in it, in all thoſe Countreys where Monaſteries were overturn'd or ſearch'd upon the Reformation. The vaſt heaps of Childrens Bones that were found in Draw-wells, and other places about them, were ſpeaking, tho not living Monuments of the horrid Impurity, as well as barbarous Cruel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of thoſe pretended Religious Communities. To inſiſt any more upon this, were to accuſe the Age of inexcuſable Ignorance in Hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtory, and therefore we ſhall conclude this Introduction with an Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation from <hi>Fox</hi>'s <hi>Acts and Monuments,</hi> That before the Reforma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion the Prieſts alone were computed to have 100000 Whores in this Kingdom; which muſt be underſtood of what the Dialect of thoſe times call'd <hi>Lemmans,</hi> from the French, <hi>L'Amante,</hi> that is, in the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dern
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:175823:3"/>
Phraſe, <hi>kept Miſſes;</hi> beſides their promiſcuous Whoredoms with the Women, they confeſſed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This horrid Uncleanneſs of the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy cannot appear in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>credible to thoſe who conſider, that beſides their being judicially given up of God to work all manner of Uncleanneſs with greedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, their Vow of Chaſtity, and being forbidden to Marry, lays them under a temptation peculiar to their Order.</p>
            <p>It will yet appear leſs ſtrange, if we conſider their way of living, and opportunity: They eat and drink of the beſt, are Careſſed in all Families of their Way; have an Advantage of knowing the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clinations, and private converſe with Women by their Auricular Confeſſion, and by their pretended Power to give Pardon; have a Door open to perſwade the Committing of one Sin for expiating a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother, and accordingly improve it.</p>
            <p>This is ſo far from being a Calumny, that the Popiſh Laity them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves in all Ages and Countreys have been ſenſible of it; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore moſt of the Popiſh Kingdoms ſollicited the Council of <hi>Trent</hi> to allow Prieſts marriage. But the Pope, for Reaſons we ſhall touch anon, did not think fit to grant it; tho' <hi>Aeneas Silvius</hi> himſelf, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwards Pope, was ſo fully convinc'd of the neceſſity of it, that he ſaid, <hi>Tho' Prieſts were forbidden to marry for very good Reaſons, yet there were better Reaſons to allow it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>They that have Travel'd in Popiſh Countreys, and obſerv'd their Prieſts and Monks, know, that generally ſpeaking, they carry about them no marks of that Auſterity and Mortification which they pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to. They look as fat and generally fatter than other Men; which is an infallible Token that they fare as well, if not better, than others do. You ſhall ſee as white and plump a hand under a Monks Hood, as in any Family of Quality; and a Foot as clean and neat many times in a Sandal, as is to be found under a Spaniſh Leather Shoe and Silk Stocking: Nor is it any Secret, that in the Neighbourhood of Convents there's as good Diet prepar'd for the uſe of Monks and Nuns, as comes to Gentlemens Tables. Nay, thoſe very places of Retirement, with their large Gardens, adorn'd with Walks and Shades, and many times water'd by pleaſant Fountains or murmuring Streams, together with their Idle way of living, ſeem to be accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modated to inſpire them with amorous Sentiments, againſt which their Vows of Chaſtity, and the Rules of their Order, are ſo far from being Preſervatives, that they only add Fewel to their Flames, and make them commit Sin with the higher reliſh. So that when they go abroad from their Monaſterys, they are like ſo many fed
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:175823:3"/>
Horſes neighing, as the Scripture expreſſes it of the luſtful <hi>Jews,</hi> after every Woman they ſee; and if they have not opportunity of giving vent to their Luſts that way, they many times do it by other methods, which Nature, as well as Religion forbids to name. This we may juſtly ſuppoſe to have been the Motive that induc'd <hi>Emanuel de Saa</hi> in his Aphoriſms to maintain that <hi>Fornication, Adultery</hi> and <hi>Sodomy</hi> did not make a Prieſt irregular, whereas <hi>Marriage</hi> did.</p>
            <p>If beſides their being forbidden to marry, we conſider that they are provided for by the ſweat of other Mens Faces, have no Families to take care of, have no hard Labour to mortify and keep them low, and are under no Obligation to ſtudy hard, we ſhall find that there's no reaſon to wonder if they be more inclinable to Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nery than any other Men whatſoever; and ſince by Experience it is found to be ſo, forbidding them Marriage may well be call'd <hi>a Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine of Devils,</hi> both as to its Original and Effects. That it comes from the Devil, the Father of Lies, and by conſequence the Author of every falſe Doctrine, is not to be controverted, ſince the Law of God and Nature commands us to increaſe and multiply, and fits us for it; and that it might be in a regular way, God himſelf inſtituted Marriage in Paradiſe, and the Apoſtle tells us, <hi>that Marriage is ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable in all:</hi> and that this Doctrine is deviliſh in its effects, is evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent from the horrid impurity of the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy abovementioned, and the miſchiefs they do by it to particular Perſons, Families, King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms and Common-wealths.</p>
            <p>We come next to take a view of the Cauſe, why the Court of <hi>Rome</hi> does ſo ſtiffly inſiſt on the Celibacy of their Clergy, which will further demonſtrate the reaſonableneſs of Guelding them to prevent their infeſting this Nation.</p>
            <p>Tho' <hi>Rome</hi> pretends to have changed her Religion, and hath actu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally changed her form of Government, by taking an Eccleſiaſtical in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of a Temporal Head; yet it's viſible ſhe hath abated nothing of her Ambition, to be Miſtriſs of the Univerſe, and did in a great mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure effect it by her Papacy, to which ſo great a part of thoſe called Chriſtian Nations ſubmitted before the Reformation. So as <hi>Cataline,</hi> when <hi>Rome</hi> was Heathen, thought it neceſſary to debauch the Women, and then to carry on his Conſpiracy againſt the Government by their Intereſt, becauſe of the influence leud Women had upon the looſe Rabble, and that they could either murder their Husbands, or bring them over to his Party. <hi>Rome</hi> ſince it became Antichriſtian, hath en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>join'd Celebacy upon her Clergy, that they might be rendered the more apt to debauch Women, and to make uſe of their Intereſt in
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:175823:4"/>
order to deprive the Civil Magiſtrates of their Right, and to uſurp the Temporal, as well as the Spiritual Sword.</p>
            <p n="1">1. Becauſe they know that Nature having inclin'd all Men to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pagate their Species, their Prieſts ſo and ſo circumſtantiated, as before-mentioned, could not poſſibly refrain from the Act, tho' they were not allow'd to do it in a regular way: and therefore ſo many Women as they debauch, which they knew by their Circumſtances and Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity, muſt needs be innumerable, ſo many Proſelytes they were ſure of.</p>
            <p n="2">2. Becauſe they knew that their Clergy being pamper'd and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrain'd from the uſe of the Marriage-Bed, muſt needs be more in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clinable to Venery than other Men, and conſequently more pleaſing Companions to inſatiable Women, and therefore the better fitted for the practice of <hi>creeping into Houſes, and leading captive ſilly Women, la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den with divers Luſts,</hi> as the Apoſtle expreſſes it.</p>
            <p n="3">3. Becauſe they knew that their Clergy by this means having an Opportunity of bringing to their Lure a Buxom Wife, who perhaps has a ſickly, weak, or abſent Husband, a Green-ſickneſs Daughter, or a wanton Maid; they would by the ſame means become Maſters in a manner of all that belong'd to the Family, have the command of their Purſes, know all their Secrets, and improve all to the advantage of the See of <hi>Rome,</hi> which indulg'd them thus with a <hi>Mahomet</hi>'s Paradiſe.</p>
            <p n="4">4. By reſtraining their Clergy from Marriage, they knew it would make them the more impetuous to ſatisfy their deſires; and that they might have the better Opportunity of doing it, they are enjoyn'd by their Directory in confeſſing Women, to examine them moſt as to the Sins of the Fleſh, which they tell 'em they muſt diſcover on pain of Damnation. This being a ready method to inflame them mutually, attended with Secrecy, and the Prieſts pretended Power of giving a Pardon, they knew it could not miſs of the deſign'd Effect; they knew alſo that ſo many of thoſe ſilly Women as they captivated, ſo many Champions and Advocates for their Religion they ſhould have in Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies, Courts, or elſewhere; for they might aſſure themſelves that ſuch Women would not eaſily part with a Religion that did ſo much gratify their depraved Appetites, by allowing them as many Men, tho' not Husbands, as they have Prieſts or Confeſſors. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore many of the wiſe Popiſh Laicks have been of Opinion themſelves, that no Man ought to confeſs a Wife but her Husband, and that a Daughter ought to be confeſſed by none but her Father.</p>
            <p n="5">5. Another, and that none of the leaſt Reaſons why they forbid Marriage to their Eccleſiaſtics, is, That if they had Wives or Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:175823:4"/>
they could not ſo eaſily be ſent on Miſſions, and encompaſs Sea and Land to make Proſelytes. They would not be ſo ready, nor ſo fit to engage in Aſſaſſinations, Conſpiracies and Rebellions againſt Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces and States, at the Commands of their Superior: Nor could they by their Whoredoms ſo much propagate the Intereſt of the great Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lot; for then their Wives would be ſo many checks and ſpies upon them.</p>
            <p>From all which it ſeems reaſonable to infer, that the beſt way to rid this Kingdom of Popiſh Prieſts, and to prevent the growth of Popery, is to make a Law, that all of them who ſhall be diſcover'd in <hi>England,</hi> except ſuch as are thought fit to be allowed to Foreign Ambaſſadors, ſhall be Gelded, as they are in <hi>Sweden;</hi> where, ſince the ſame was En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted into a Law, and practis'd upon a few of them, that Kingdom hath never been infeſted with Popiſh Clergy, or Plots, nor their Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men reproach'd with want of Chaſtity.</p>
            <p>This will appear the more reaſonable, if we conſider that the Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vock they are allow'd to make of Womens Chaſtity, is one of the prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipal things that induces luſtful Fellows to take <hi>Romiſh</hi> Orders upon them, and to engage in deſperate Deſigns to promote the Intereſt of that Church. This any man may eaſily be convinc'd of, that will give himſelf leave to conſider what dangers other men of better Principles, and who may have opportunities of ſatisfying Nature by lawful Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, do many times expoſe themſelves to, for the Satisfaction of their bruitiſh Paſſions, and how they frequently ſacrifice Honour, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, and Eſtate, with the Peace of their Families and Conſciences, to their irregular Appetites of that ſort.</p>
            <p>The Caſe then being thus, let's conſider what a deluge of Unclean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs may be pour'd out upon this Nation by 1000 or 2000, ſuppoſing there were no more of thoſe Popiſh Eccleſiaſticks in <hi>England</hi> at a time; eſpecially ſince they look upon it to be their intereſt to debauch the Nation, as one of the beſt Expedients to advance Popery, as was evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent from the Practice of the late Reigns: and therefore it ſeems to be the natural way of obviating the growth of Popery, to make the Romiſh Eccleſiaſticks uncapable of promoting it by that Method which they like beſt, and find moſt ſucceſsful.</p>
            <p>It will ſtill appear to be more reaſonable, becauſe they have vow'd Chaſtity, and by their own Confeſſion have no occaſion for thoſe Semi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Veſſels; therefore if they reſolve to live as they have Sworn to do, they would willingly unman themſelves as <hi>Origen</hi> did; ſo far would they be from having any reaſon to complain, if others ſhould do it for them.</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:175823:5"/>
            <p>It can no ways be reckon'd cruel, ſince it may be done without ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zard of Life, as common experience ſhews both in Man and Beaſt, and by conſequence leſs to be complain'd of, than thoſe Laws which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demn them to the Gallows. There have been more Prieſts put to death in <hi>England,</hi> than ever were gelded in <hi>Sweden;</hi> yet Experience teaches us it hath not had near ſo good an Effect. This is demonſtrable from the many Conſpiracies againſt our Princes and Nation, that the Prieſts have form'd ſince the enacting of thoſe Laws, and from the great Progreſs their Idolatry makes among us at this very day; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as <hi>Sweden,</hi> ſince the enacting of that Law, hath been liable to none of theſe misfortunes. This Law of <hi>Castration</hi> occaſion'd a pleaſant Rail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ery upon the Jeſuits at <hi>Bruſſels</hi> by Queen <hi>Chriſtina</hi> of <hi>Sweden.</hi> When thoſe Fathers came to Congratulate her there upon her Converſion, they entertain'd her, among other things, with the wonderful Effects of their Miſſions in the <hi>Indies,</hi> and other remote parts: That Princeſs applauded their Zeal, but at the ſame time rebuk'd their Indifference for her Countrey of <hi>Sweden,</hi> where their endeavours were ſo much needed: She pleaſantly told them, That tho' the Law of <hi>Caſtration</hi> was a Bar in their way, they ought not to prefer the keeping of thoſe things of which they ſtood in no need, and of which ſhe hop'd they made no uſe to the advancement of the Catholick Faith. But this, tho' the ſevereſt Reproof in the World, has never been able to bring the Romiſh Clergy to ſo much ſenſe of their Duty, as to renew their At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempts of converting <hi>Sweden.</hi> This may ſerve to confirm the ſtory told us of an old Capuchin in the <hi>Menagiana,</hi> the Works of the Abbot <hi>Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage,</hi> that he rejected the Advice of his Phyſicians to be cut of the Stone, for fear it ſhould make him Impotent, tho' he was then 80 Years of Age.</p>
            <lg>
               <l>Namque ad Vivendum caſtrari valde recuſat,</l>
               <l>Et propter vitam vivendi perdere cauſam.</l>
            </lg>
            <p>The Romiſh Clergy have ſo much accuſtom'd themſelves to thoſe impure Pleaſures, that they will be ſure to avoid thoſe Countreys where they muſt be render'd uncapable of enjoying them.</p>
            <p>If it be thought that the Laws already made, will be more effectual againſt them, there's no need of repealing them, tho' a new one of <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtration</hi> be added. Since that hath had ſo good an Effect in <hi>Sweden,</hi> we have no reaſon to deſpair of the like here. It's generally concluded, that our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Women are as tempting as any in <hi>Europe,</hi> and are therefore as likely to prevail on a Romiſh Prieſt to venture hanging to enjoy their Favours as any others: But if they be rendered unca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable of it, the tempaation will have no force; and ſo the Prieſts will
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:175823:5"/>
ſave their Lives, our Women will preſerve their Chaſtity, and our Religion and Liberty will be freed from their Attacques.</p>
            <p>The only Objection of weight that can be made againſt it is, that it may provoke our Popiſh Allies, and other Popiſh Princes, to treat Proteſtant Miniſters in the like manner. To which we anſwer, That, admitting it ſhould be ſo, it is not half ſo bad as to have them broke on the Wheel, Hang'd, or ſent to the Gallies. In the next place, there's not the like Reaſon for treating Proteſtant Miniſters in that manner, for they generally marry; or if they be guilty of Uncleanneſs, are thruſt from the Miniſtry. And in the laſt place, there's no reaſon why we ſhould have any more regard to our Allies, or other Popiſh Princes, than they have to us. We hear every day of the cruel Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution in <hi>France</hi> and <hi>Germany,</hi> notwithſtanding our mildneſs to the Papiſts here; ſo that our enacting a Law of <hi>Castration,</hi> cannot poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly make them perſecute the Proteſtants more ſeverely than they do, but may rather put a ſtop to it.</p>
            <p>And indeed it is to be wondred at, that the Proteſtants ſhould be ſo much wanting in their Zeal, and ſo little ſenſible of their own Intereſt; when we have ſo Warlike and Zealous a <hi>Proteſtant Prince,</hi> upon the Throne of <hi>Great Britain,</hi> as not to agree on Methods for obliging the Papiſts to forbear that barbarous Perſecution of their Brethren. En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours of that Nature were us'd in ſome of thoſe Reigns when Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pery had ſo much Intereſt at Court, that it ſeem'd to have a ſhare of the Throne; therefore it's ſtrange if nothing ſhould be attempted to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards it in this Reign. To effect this would, humanly ſpeaking, ſeem to be no difficult work, ſince the Naval Strength of <hi>Europe</hi> is in the hands of the Proteſtants; and that the ſtrength of <hi>Great Britain</hi> and <hi>Holland</hi> is now under the Command of one Prince, who is the <hi>Hero</hi> of his Age.</p>
            <p>This our own Safety ſeems to require, and charity and compaſſion to our Brethren beyond Sea does loudly call for; but if for reaſons of State, or otherwiſe, it be found impracticable for us to interpoſe in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half of perſecuted Proteſtants abroad, there's nothing can hinder us, if we be wiling to ſecure our ſelves againſt Popery at home, by put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting the old Laws in Execution, or Enacting new ones.</p>
            <p>This ſeems to be abſolutely neceſſary, if we conſider, either the State of the Proteſtants beyond Sea, or our own Condition at home.</p>
            <p>If we look abroad, we ſhall find the Proteſtant Intereſt, which was once ſo conſiderable in <hi>France,</hi> quite ruin'd; and one of the chife Cauſes of its being ſo, was the neglect of our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Governments ſince Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi>'s time: we have done nothing effectual for them ſince then, which was a mighty overſight, both in reſpect of Duty and Intereſt.
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:175823:6"/>
That it was our Duty, will ſcarcely be deny'd by any Man that has any true Impreſſions of the Proteſtant Religion. That it was our In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt is demonſtrable, becauſe, had the Proteſtants of <hi>France</hi> been ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported by our Meditation and Aſſiſtance, they would never have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curr'd in any ambitious deſign of their Monarchs againſt the Proteſtant Intereſt, or this Nation; and perhaps the fears of that Court, that they might prove a Curb on their Deſigns of that Nature, was none of the leaſt cauſes of their having ruin'd them by the moſt ungrateful, as well as the moſt barbarous Perſecution that ever was known. From all which it will naturally reſult, that it is the Intereſt of <hi>England</hi> to ſave, if poſſible, the Remnant of the Proteſtants in <hi>France,</hi> by ſome Effectual Interpoſition.</p>
            <p>If we look a little further into the State of the Proteſtants of the Valleys of <hi>Piedmont,</hi> we ſhall find that Antient Church almoſt totally ruin'd and diſperſt. If we turn our Eye towards <hi>Hungary, Tranſilvania,</hi> and <hi>Poland,</hi> the Reformed Intereſt is almoſt quite exterminated in thoſe Countreys, as it is totally ruin'd in <hi>Bohemia:</hi> What danger it is liable to in the Neighbouring Countrey of <hi>Saxony,</hi> is known to every one, ſince that Country, whoſe Prince was the firſt that embrac'd the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation, is now under a Popiſh Government; and if we come near<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er home to the <hi>Palatinate,</hi> there we ſhall alſo find a Proteſtant Church, once the moſt flouriſhing, and beſt reformed in all <hi>Germany,</hi> under an unreaſonable and cruel Perſecution. If we conſider the Treaty of <hi>Reſwick,</hi> by that we ſhall find the <hi>German</hi> Proteſtants deſpoil'd of eight or nine hundred Churches: The once famous Proteſtant City of <hi>Stras<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burgh</hi> deliver'd in Prey to the Church of <hi>Rome;</hi> and the Proteſtants in <hi>Alſace,</hi> and the Neighbouring Principalities on each ſide, as the Dut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chy of <hi>Montbelliard,</hi> County of <hi>Veldents,</hi> &amp;c. ſubject to Popiſh Incroach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments. In a word, if we look throughout the whole <hi>Empire,</hi> and take a view of the Diet at <hi>Ratisbon,</hi> we ſhall find the Popiſh Intereſt every whene rampant, and Incroaching upon the Reformation, contrary to the Fundamental Laws, and moſt ſolemn Treaties of the <hi>Empire.</hi> If we caſt an Eye upon <hi>Swiſſerland,</hi> the little Republick of <hi>Geneva,</hi> and the Principality of <hi>Neufchatel,</hi> there alſo we ſhall find the Proteſtant Intereſt threatned, and languiſhing.</p>
            <p>If we look Northward, there we find the Proteſtant Kingdoms of <hi>Sweden</hi> and <hi>Denmark</hi> ready to ingage in a War with one another, and that the Quarrels betwixt them are fomented by thoſe who carry on an Intereſt which is deſtructive both to the Proteſtant Religion, and the Civil Liberties of <hi>Europe.</hi> This is ſufficient to diſcover the bad State of the Proteſtant Intereſt abroad.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:175823:6"/>
            <p>If we conſider the Poſture of Affairs at home, it's evident from a late printed Letter, ſaid to be wrote by a worthy Biſhop, and Dedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated to a Member of Parliament, that Popery comes in upon us like a Flood. It is not to be denied that there's a Party in the three Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, who favour the Title of an Abdicated Popiſh Prince and his pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Succeſſion, againſt the preſent Government, and the Succeſſion eſtabliſh'd by Law. It is not to be forgot, that their Intereſt was ſo ſtrong as to advance a Popiſh King to our Throne; and tho' they could not keep him there, becauſe he diſmounted himſelf by a ſurious Career, yet they have endanger'd us ſince by repeated Plots againſt his preſent Majeſty's Life, and endeavouring to bring in a French In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vaſion upon us. It is alſo known, that there are mighty diſcontents ſomented and nouriſh'd in all the three Nations, in relation to Trade; Parties, and different Pretenſions; and that this gives the Popiſh Cler<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gy an opportunity of adding fewel to our Flames, which makes it like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe evident that the Proteſtant Intereſt is in danger at home.</p>
            <p>This is further demonſtrable from the Trouble the Papiſts have from time to time given, and continue to give to our Government and Parliaments; what's the meaning elſe of thoſe Proclamations former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and lately omitted, commanding Papiſts to retire from <hi>London,</hi> &amp;c. What elſe is the meaning of thoſe Bills brought in to prevent their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>inheriting their Proteſtant Heirs, and to hinder their ſending Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren abroad to foreign Seminaries, to be bred up in Idolatry, or made Prieſts, Monks and Nuns? This, beſides the danger that accrues there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by to our Religion and Liberties, takes vaſt Summs of Money out of the Kingdom yearly. They likewiſe give trouble to our Parliaments, by bringing in Bills for diſcovering Eſtates and Money given to ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſtitious Uſes, which is every way mighty prejudicial to the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and enables the Papiſts to breed Vipers in our Bowels, in order to rend us in pieces.</p>
            <p>Then ſince it is undeniable that we are in danger from the Papiſts, whether we conſider the State of Affairs at home or abroad, and that the Laws hitherto enacted have not been able to prevent the recourſe of Popiſh Prieſts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> nor the growth of Popery in this Kingdom; what ſhould hinder us from trying new Methods, and particularly this Law of <hi>Caſtration?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It would certainly be a puniſhment very proper for them, and might make them read their Sin in their Judgment; ſince it's evident that by their own perſonal Villany, and their looſe Doctrine of Pardons, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which incourages People in Licentiouſneſs, they make more Proſelytes than by any other method.</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:175823:7"/>
            <p>Thoſe, who perhaps would ſcruple to be any ways Inſtrumental in taking theſe Prieſts, when the Penalty inflicted upon them by Law is Death, would not have reaſon to be ſo ſcrupulous to take and diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver them when the puniſhment is only <hi>Caſtration,</hi> and therefore would be more diligent to put the Laws in Execution upon them.</p>
            <p>It muſt alſo be reckon'd a deſerv'd Puniſhment, ſince under the Seal of Confeſſion they commit Uncleanneſs with thoſe they have the Truſt of as Ghoſtly Fathers, ſo that it is a ſort of ſpiritual Inceſt, and a deſtroying People with Arms that make no Report; both which Crimes are Capital in all well-govern'd States, and therefore the pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment of <hi>Caſtration</hi> in ſuch a Caſe muſt needs be accounted mild.</p>
            <p>If it be objected, that tho ſome of the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy be guilty of Incontinence, yet all of them are not ſo, and therefore ſuch only are to be puniſh'd in that manner as are convicted of the Crime: It's eaſy to anſwer, That it is equally true, that all of them are not guilty of Conſpiring againſt the Government, nor is it poſſible to convict all of 'em of perverting the Subjects; yet the <hi>27th</hi> of <hi>Eliz.</hi> makes it Treaſon for any Popiſh Prieſt, bred up beyond Sea, to be here, or to return in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to <hi>England</hi> without ſubmitting to the Government, and taking the Oath of Supremacy. And indeed it is but reaſonable it ſhould be ſo, for their being here ſuppoſes their Deſign; and therefore there's as much reaſon to puniſh them, tho' we cannot prove the Overt Acts upon them, as there is to puniſh Thieves for coming into our Houſes in an illegal manner, tho' we cannot prove that they have robb'd us, or ſtole any thing. If we find a Wolfe or other Beaſt of Prey among our Flocks, we take their deſign of deſtroying them for granted, and treat them accordingly, tho' we don't ſee the Limbs of our Cattle in their Mouths. And therefore ſince the Practices and Principles of the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy are ſo well known, their being found in the Nation ought to have ſufficient Conviction.</p>
            <p>It ſtill remains a Queſtion, how they ſhall be diſcovered? But the Anſwer is at hand: Let a competent and certain Reward be propos'd for ſuch as ſhall do it, and the like Reward, and a Pardon to any of their own Number that ſhall diſcover the reſt; or let proviſion be made for ſome of every Engliſh Seminary beyond Sea that turn Proteſtants, plant ſome of them in the ſeveral Ports of the Kingdom; and let ſome of each of thoſe Seminaries be likewiſe conſtantly in <hi>London</hi> to aſſiſt in Searches, and view thoſe that are taken upon ſuſpition: And at the ſame time, let proviſion be made for ſuch as will inform of all the Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Clergy that haunt the great Families of that Opinion in <hi>England,</hi> and we need not doubt of an effectual diſcovery in a little time: for
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:175823:7"/>
beſides the influence that the hopes of a Reward will have, thoſe Goat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh Fellows, the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy, do many times diſoblige Families of their own way, by attempting to debauch their Wives, Children, or Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants, ſome of whom have ſo much Virtue as to reject the Temptati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and to hate the Tempters; and many times their blind Zeal occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions them likewiſe to take indeſcreet Methods to pervert Proteſtant Servants, who would not be wanting, in caſe of ſuch proviſion as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove-mention'd to diſcover thoſe dangerous Fellows.</p>
            <p>To inflict this puniſhment of <hi>Caſtration</hi> upon them, is ſo much the leſs to be thought cruel or unreaſonable, ſince it is ſo ordinary in <hi>Ita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> and other Popiſh Countries, for the meaner fort of People to geld their own Sons, that they may make the better market of them for ſinging Boys, and Muſitians, or to be Catamites to Cardinals, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Dignitaries of the Romiſh Church. In thoſe hot Countries the Roman Clergy are much addicted to that damnable and unnatural Crime: and ſuch of them as are not, keep lewd Women almoſt avow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edly; they are indeed more upon the Reſerve, and live according to the Maxim of <hi>Cauté</hi> tho not <hi>Caſté,</hi> in ſuch Countreys where the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment is Reformed, or where the Proteſtants are numerous; but then they are under the greater temptation to perpetrate their Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lanies, on the pretext of Confeſſing women: therefore there's the more Reaſon to Enact a Law of <hi>Caſtration</hi> againſt them in this Kingdom.</p>
            <p>We have the more ground to think, that ſuch a Law duly executed, would have a good Effect, becauſe the Luſt of the Fleſh is ſo bewitch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and natural to the greateſt part of mankind, and continues to have a predominacy in them for ſo great a part of their lives, that it hath occaſion'd, and does occaſion more diſorders, and is apter to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gage men, over whom it obtains the aſcendant, in more deſperate un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertakings than any other paſſion whatever. Hiſtories are full of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amples of Princes and great Men, that have ruin'd then ſelves and their Countreys in purſuit of their irregular Amours. We have no need to turn over foreign Stories, or to go out of our own Nation for proofs of this. It is not ſo long ago as to be forgot, ſince we had the chief Affairs of State manag'd, and Parliaments diſſolv'd, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at the beck of <hi>Courtiſans.</hi> The Intereſt of <hi>Popery</hi> and <hi>Tyranny</hi> in the late Reigns was chiefly advanc'd by ſuch.</p>
            <p>Do we not find, even in private perſons of all Ranks, that where that paſſion is not kept in due bounds, or cur'd by the proper Reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies of a ſuitable Match, that Honour, Health, and Eſtates, nay Life it ſelf, is many times ſacrific'd to the pleaſure of the Fleſh; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Apoſtle had Reaſon as well as Revelation on his ſide, when he
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:175823:8"/>
rank'd all that is in the World under the three Heads of <hi>the Luſt of the Fleſh, the Luſt of the Eye,</hi> and <hi>the Pride of Life;</hi> and gave that of the Fleſh the preference. It is plain from Experience, that the other two are made generally ſubſervient to it, as is viſibly every day from that ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs in Jewels, Apparel and Houſhold Furniture, and the vaſt expence which the Gallants of both Sexes put themſelves to in one or all of theſe, in order to obtain the Favour of their <hi>Paramours.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>From all which we may make this Inference, that if the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy were made uncapable by a Law of enjoying that which they account the greateſt pleaſure of Life, they would avoid thoſe Countreys where ſuch Laws are put in execution, as they would avoid the Plague. 'Twould be happy if by this means we could deliver our Poſterity from thoſe Conſpiracies, Civil Wars, Dreadful Fires, Maſſacrees, Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaſſinations of Princes, and other miſchiefs which theſe Kingdoms have been liable to from the Papiſts, and againſt which all our other Laws have hither to ſignified but little to preſerve us.</p>
            <p>We have alſo found, by ſad Experience, that they have had ſo much influence as to get the Aſcendant over ſome of our Princes, by tempt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing them, as they have done the <hi>French</hi> King, with the hopes of an ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolute Sway, and we know not what Viſionary Empires. By this means they prevail'd with them to overthrow our Laws, the recovery of which hath coſt the Nation ſo much Blood and Treaſure, that after Ages are like to feel the ſmart of it: Tho' they have run one of our Princes off the Stage, and have well-nigh ruin'd their great Champion beyond Sea, as they did formerly the <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Monarchy, by ſpurring on thoſe Princes to perſecute Proteſtants, and eſtabliſh Deſpotical Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment. They will never give over that Game, but inſpire all Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces to whom they can have acceſs, either by themſelves or others, with one or both of thoſe Deſigns; and therefore it is the Intereſt of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> to uſe all poſſible means to ſecure the Nation againſt thoſe <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergymen, for which <hi>Caſtration</hi> is humbly conceiv'd to be the propereſt Method, and is ſo far from being cruelty, that it may well be reckon'd as great a piece of Clemency to <hi>Romiſh</hi> Prieſts, as Tranſportation is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of the Gallows to other Condemned Criminals.</p>
            <p>In ſhort, it will be ſo far from being a real diskindneſs to the Popiſh Laics of this Nation, that it will be the greateſt piece of Friendſhip to them imaginable: this we hope they will be the more readily convinc'd of, if their Wives, Daughters, and Maid-ſervants, cry out againſt this Law, for then to be ſure they have ſome particular concern in the matter.</p>
            <p>We hope that our Popiſh Laics in <hi>England</hi> are Men of as good Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation as thoſe in other Countreys, and particularly in <hi>France</hi> and
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:175823:8"/>
               <hi>Italy,</hi> where their very Proverbs are ſufficient to demonſtrate, that they have no great Opinion of their Clergymens Chaſtity. It is not poſſible to expoſe thoſe goatiſh Fellows with more ſeverity and contempt, than the <hi>Italians</hi> do by ſaying <hi>fate Lui Corunna,</hi> by way of ſarcaſm, of a Stal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion that they don't think performs his part; alluding to the Prieſts ſhaven Crowns as if that Sacerdotal Character were ſufficient even to invigorate a Horſe. Their other Proverb of <hi>fate lo Prete,</hi> let's make him a Prieſt, when they have any ungovernable Wanton in a Family, that over-runs all their Females, is skin to the other; and their cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring their Stone-Horſes with a Monk's Frock, when they find them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>different for a Mare in ſeaſon, is a ſcandalous Reproof of thoſe bruitiſh Clergymen. Anſwerable to theſe is the <hi>French</hi> Proverb;</p>
            <lg>
               <l>Qui vent tenir nette Maiſon</l>
               <l>Qu'il n'y ſouffre ni petri ni Moin ni pigeon.</l>
            </lg>
            <p>Comparing the Popiſh Clergy to the Pigeons for their venerious Incli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations; and may be Engliſhed thus,</p>
            <lg>
               <l>They that would keep their Houſes Chaſt and Neat,</l>
               <l>From thence muſt Prieſts, Monks, Nuns, and Pigeons beat.</l>
            </lg>
            <p>As all Proverbs of that ſort are founded upon ſomething univerſally known or conceiv'd to be true, it is not at all for the Honour of the Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Clergy, that their Chaſtity ſhould be thus reflected upon in Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treys where they are the ſole Directors of Conſcience, and have their Religion eſtabliſh'd by Law.</p>
            <p>But that which fixes yet more upon them, is, that in the Pope's Chancery the Tax for eating Eggs in <hi>Lent,</hi> is greater than that for So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>domy; and the Penalty upon a Prieſt that Marries, is greater than up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thoſe that commit that monſtrous and unnatural Villany juſt now mention'd. From all which it is manifeſt, that they did not ſpeak as random who inform'd us that the Celibacy of ſuch an innumerable multitude of Popiſh Eccleſiaſticks, is the <hi>maximum Arcanum dominationis Papalis,</hi> and <hi>that the Prieſts Teſticles are the greateſt Promoters of the Pave'd Empire.</hi> This will appear yet more plain, that it is of the higheſt Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portance to them, ſince the Church of <hi>Rome</hi> maintains, that Marriage is a Sacrament, and that all Sacraments confer Grace, and yet denies it to her Clergy; a manifeſt Indication that they have their graceleſs de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns to promote by it, eſpecially ſince at the ſame time the want of thoſe parts which they will not allow them to make uſe of in a regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar way, renders them uncapable of being Prieſts according to their Canons; but yet they are ſo kind to their gelded Martyrs, as to allow it to be ſufficient if they have them about them, in Powder, or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther way.</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:175823:9"/>
            <p>Theſe things confirm, in a literal ſenſe, the odious Characters given the Church of <hi>Rome</hi> in the <hi>Revelations,</hi> Chap. 17, 18, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> As, <hi>the great Whore, with whom the Kings and Inhabitants of the Earth have committed Fornication; the Mother of Harlots, and Abominations of the Earth, having a Golden Cup in her hand full of Abominations, and of the Filthineſs of her Fornications,</hi> &amp;c. Then ſince by the teſtimony of God and Man, the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy is ſuch an impure and laſcivious Crew, it makes a Law of <hi>Caſtration</hi> a juſt and adequate Puniſhment for them.</p>
            <p>To conclude; Since our King and Parliament have both teſtified their Zeal and Forwardneſs to ſuppreſs Immorality and Profaneneſs, it follows naturally that ſuch a Law as this deſerves their ſerious Thoughts; for it is impoſſible to ſuppreſs this reigning Vice, ſo long as thoſe goatiſh Fellows are ſuffered to ſwarm among us. They not only corrupt the Morals of People themſelves by ſuch Practices and Principles as above-mention'd, but bring over and encourage others to do it; particularly thoſe <hi>Itatians,</hi> &amp;c. who ſell and print <hi>Aretin's Poſtures;</hi> and in order to debauch the minds of Women, and to make them guilty of unnatural Crimes, invent and ſell'em ſuch things as Modeſty forbids to name. 'Tis evident, that as Popery advanc'd up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on us in the late Reigns, Debauchery gain'd ground at the ſame time, for they naturally make way for one another; and therefore we can never ſuppreſs Immorality, without ſecuring our ſelves effectually a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Popery. If this ſhould be attempted by a Law of <hi>Caſtration</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt <hi>Romiſh</hi> Prieſts, it muſt be own'd that it would be more Chari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table and Humane to ſave our ſelves from Popiſh Superſtition, and all its miſchievous Conſequences, by that Method alone, than to Practice it, together with other Puniſhments, upon ſuch of thoſe Wretches as come to the Gibbet for Treaſon; the cutting off their Privities in ſuch caſes, and throwing 'em in the Fire, juſt before they be totally bereft of Life, can be of no manner of uſe, whereas <hi>Caſtration</hi> alone beforehand might have ſav'd us from the Danger of their Plots, and prevented themſelves from coming to the Gallows.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
